Inventory of the Reuben Bromstein papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Reuben Bromstein papers
1951-2015
2016C35
Hoover Institution Archives
7 manuscript boxes, 7 oversize boxes (16.9 linear feet)
Correspondence, printed matter, photographs and memorabilia relating to communist youth activities in Canada and especially to the 3rd World Festival of Youth and Students for Peace and Friendship in East Berlin in 1951.
Bromstein, Reuben.
Box 13-14
Box 1-12
Access
The collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2016.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Canadian communist youth leader.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, printed matter, photographs and memorabilia relating to communist youth activities in Canada and especially to the 3rd World Festival of Youth and Students for Peace and Friendship in East Berlin in 1951.
Arrangement Note
The Reuben Bromstein papers are arranged in alphabetical order, with descriptions provided by the donor. An additonal item description list can be found in the boxes at the start of each alphabetical binder.
Communism--Canada.; World Festival of Youth and Students for Peace and Friendship.
- Binder A: "A Canadian Communist at the 1951 Berlin World Youth Festival, Photographs"
  Scope and Content Note
  Materials from the 3rd World Festival of Youth and Students for Peace and the World University Summer Games XI.
  - A1-A3, 1951 (Box 1)
  - Binder A (Box 1)
  - A4 (Box 1)
  - A4: Photographs (Box 8)
  - A5 (Box 1)
  - A5-A7: Photographs (Box 8)
- Binder B: "East Berlin World Youth Festival Events, Documents, and Souvenirs,", 1951
  - B1-B5 (Box 1)
  - B6 (Box 10)
  - B7 (Box 1)
  - B7 (Box 14)
  - B8 (Box 10)
  - B9 (Box 13)
  - B10 (Box 9)
  - B11-B22 (Box 1)
  - BB: Souvenirs and pins (Box 7)
- Binder C: "From Communist Childhood to Communist National Youth Leader and Resignation,", 1940s-1950s
  Materials related to communist youth, the Labour Progressive Party and the National Federation of Labor Youth, as well as the newspaper Champion.
  - C1 (Box 2)
  - C2: Souvenirs and pins (Box 7)
  - C3-C4 (Box 2)
  - C5 (Box 13)
  - C6 (Box 10)
  - C7-C9 (Box 2)
  - C10: Champion, A Canadian Communist Youth Newspaper (Box 2)
  - C11, C12 (Box 9)
  - C13-C15 (Box 2)
  - C15 (Box 10)
  - C16 (Box 2)
  - C17 (Box 12)
  - C18 (Box 2)
- Binder D: "Communists and Peter Seeger Involve Young People Through Folk Singing: The 'Travellers,' My Songs,", 1955-2014
  Material related to involving young people in communist causes through music, including material related to Pete Seeger's 1955 Canadian tour and the folk group "The Travellers"
  - Binder D (Box 2)
  - D1-D4 (Box 2)
  - D5 (Box 2)
  - D5-D6 (Box 9)
  - D7-D10 (Box 2)
  - D11 (Box 9)
  - D12 (Box 2)
  - D13 (Box 10)
  - D14-D19 (Box 2)
- Binder E: "My Communist Musicals: 'Little Baul Buyan' and 'Johhny's Fishing Rod,'", 1950
  Musicals written and producedto involve young people and raise money for the communist youth paper Champion
  - Binder E (Box 3)
  - E1-E2 (Box 3)
  - E3-E4 (Box 3)
  - E5 (Box 3)
  - E5 (Box 10)
  - E6-E7 (Box 3)
  - E7 (Box 10)
  - E8-E10 (Box 3)
  - E11 (Box 3)
  - E11 (Box 13)
  - E12 (Box 3)
  - E12 (Box 10)
  - E13-E14 (Box 3)
  - E15-E17 (Box 3)
- Binder F: "After Communism: Public Relations and Leagal Career, Promoting Free Markets, USA Communist Clearance, Interfaith and Anti-Suicide Bombin g Campa igns,", 1960s-2015
  Materials related to Bromstein's work in retail advertizing, public relations, free market and comprtition law, and interfaith work.
  - Binder F (Box 3)
  - F1 (Box 3)
  - F2: Contains DVD (Box 3)
  - F3 (Box 3)
  - F4-F5 (Box 3)
  - F6-F7 (Box 3)
  - F7 (Box 13)
  - F8 (Box 3)
  - F9 (Box 3)
  - F9 (Box 10)
  - F10 (Box 3)
  - F11, F12 (Box 3)
  - F11, F12 (Box 10)
  - F13 (Box 4)
  - F13 (Box 13)
  - F14 (Box 13)
  - F15-F18 (Box 4)
  - F18 (Box 10)
  - F19 (Box 4)
  - F20-F21 (Box 4)
  - F22-F23 (Box 4)
  - F23 (Box 10)
  - F24-F30 (Box 4)
- Binder G: Additional Materials
  - G1: Slides from the Berlin World Youth Festival, 1951 (Box 4)
  - G2: "Festival" Daily Newspapers, 1951 (Box 12)
  - G3: 1951 East Berlin World Youth Festival Souvenirs (oversized items) (Box 14)
  - G4: Champion, A Canadian Communist Youth Newspaper, 1951-1955 (Box 11)
  - G6: "Sing Out" Songbooks (Box 5)
  - G7: Paul Bunyan research materials (Box 5)
  - G8: "Dynamic Change and Accountability in A Canadian Market Economy,", 1976-1977 (Box 6)
  - G9: "Suicide Bombing: Parliament Speaks" (Box 5)
  - Cartoons from the Communist Daily Worker (Box 12)